https://writers.ns.ca/privacy-policy/

Poetry in Motion
“Journeys” (2020)
“Home” (2019)
Poetry in Motion
“Journeys” (2020)
“Home” (2019)
PRIVACY POLICY
The Writers’ Federation of Nova Scotia (“WFNS”) is committed to protecting your personal information. This Privacy Policy sets out the WFNS’s policy with respect to the collection, use and disclosure of such personal information via the website www.writers.ns.ca and via other communications we have with you. For the purposes of this Policy, the term “personal information” means information that can be used to personally identify you or any information which is directly associated with any such information.
WFNS limits the collection, use and disclosure of personal information to what is necessary to conduct its business, serving the needs of its membership and providing services to the public. If you do not consent to the terms of the Policy, please do not provide us with your personal information.
SECTION 1 – WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT: We only collect information about you if we have a reason to do so — for example, to provide our Services, to communicate with you, or to make our Services better. We collect this information from three sources: if and when you provide information to us, automatically through operating our Services, and from outside sources. Here are some examples of information you provide to us:     Basic account information: We ask for basic information from you in order to set up your account. For example, we require members to provide an email address and password, along with a username or name. You may provide us with more information — like your address and other information you want to share.     Public profile information: If you become a member of WFNS we collect the information that you provide for your public profile. So if you have an account, your username is part of that public profile, along with any other information you put into your public profile, like a photo or Biographical description. Your public profile information is just that — public — so please keep that in mind when deciding what information you would like to include.     Payment and contact information: If you buy something from us, we’ll collect information to process those payments and contact you.  Additionally, during payments with PayPal, you’ll provide additional personal and payment information like your name, credit card information, and contact information (see Section 4- PayPal).We also keep a record of the purchases you’ve made.
SECTION 2 – CONSENT:     How do you get my consent? When you provide us with personal information to complete a transaction, verify your credit card, place an order, arrange for a delivery or return a purchase, we imply that you consent to our collecting it and using it for that specific reason only. If we ask for your personal information for a secondary reason, like marketing, we will either ask you directly for your expressed consent, or provide you with an opportunity to say no.      How do I withdraw my consent? If you change your mind after you opt-in, you may withdraw your consent for us to contact you, for the continued collection, use or disclosure of your information, at anytime, by contacting us at communications@writers.ns.ca
SECTION 3 – DISCLOSURE: WFNS will not sell, trade or rent your personal information to any party. WFNS will not disclose any of your personal information to any third party except (i) where such party provides services to us in furtherance of the permitted use of such information and where such third person has agreed to be bound by equivalent terms to this Privacy Policy; (ii) as may be required by law; or (iii) as may be required during any due diligence process reasonably undertaken, provided that such third party is bound by obligations as least as restrictive as those contained in the Policy.
SECTION 4 – PAYPAL: Purchases on our website are processed through PayPal. They provide us with the online e-commerce platform that allows us to sell our memberships, products and services to you. Your data is stored through Paypal’s data storage, databases and the general Paypal application. They store your data on a secure server behind a firewall. For more information, see PayPal’s privacy policy here>
SECTION 5 – THIRD-PARTY SERVICES: In general, the third-party providers used by us will only collect, use and disclose your information to the extent necessary to allow them to perform the services they provide to us. However, certain third-party service providers, such as payment gateways and other payment transaction processors, have their own privacy policies in respect to the information we are required to provide to them for your purchase-related transactions. For these providers, we recommend that you read their privacy policies so you can understand the manner in which your personal information will be handled by these providers. In particular, remember that certain providers may be located in or have facilities that are located a different jurisdiction than either you or us. So if you elect to proceed with a transaction that involves the services of a third-party service provider, then your information may become subject to the laws of the jurisdiction(s) in which that service provider or its facilities are located.     Once you leave our website or are redirected to a third-party website or application, you are no longer governed by this Privacy Policy or our website’s Terms of Service. Links: When you click links on our website, they may direct you away from our site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other sites and encourage you to read their privacy statements. Google Analytics: Our store may use Google Analytics to help us learn about who visits our site and what pages are being looked at.
SECTION 6 – SECURITY: To protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions and follow industry best practices to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed. If you provide us with your credit card information, the information is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL) and stored with a AES-256 encryption.  Although no method of transmission over the Internet or electronic storage is 100% secure, we follow all PCI-DSS requirements and implement additional generally accepted industry standards.
SECTION 7 – COOKIES: Parts of our website may make use of “cookie” technology to measure site activity and to customize information to your personal tastes. A cookie is an element of data that a website can send to your browser, which may then store the cookie on your hard drive. So, when you come back to visit us again, we can tailor information to suit your individual preferences. The goal is to save you time and provide you with a more meaningful visit.
SECTION 8 – AGE OF CONSENT: By using this site, you represent that you are at least the age of majority in your state or province of residence, or that you are the age of majority in your state or province of residence and you have given us your consent to allow any of your minor dependents to use this site.
SECTION 9 – CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY: We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on the website. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here that it has been updated, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we use and/or disclose it.
QUESTIONS AND CONTACT INFORMATION: If you would like to access, correct, amend or delete any personal information we have about you, would like to register a complaint, or simply want more information, please contact our Privacy Compliance Officer at communications@writers.ns.ca
1113 Marginal RoadHalifax, NS B3H 4P7902 423 8116contact@writers.ns.caPrivacy Policy
Follow us:
Instagram
Facebook
Twitter
WFNS Membership
Programs & Awards
Projects & Events
Workshops
Resources
Author Spotlights
About Us
Home
Operational Investors
The Writers’ Federation of Nova Scotia is based in Kjipuktuk, in Mi’kma’ki, the ancestral and unceded territory of the Mi’kmaq People. This territory is covered by the “Treaties of Peace and Friendship,” which Mi’kmaq and Wolastoqiyik (Maliseet) Peoples first signed with the British Crown in 1725.The treaties do not deal with surrender of lands and resources but in fact recognize Mi’kmaq and Wolastoqiyik (Maliseet) title and establish the rules for an ongoing relationship between nations.
© Writers’ Federation of Nova Scotia, 2020. All rights reserved.
Scroll to Top
